

Hardik Chaudhary

Java||AWS Cloud||Web Development

Around 2 years of IT experience in Software development and Operations support in Windows, Linux, and Unix environments. Providing troubleshooting and client support for critical infrastructure in 24*7 support model. Experienced in working with different technologies such as Java, C++, JavaScript, NodeJS etc.

hardikchaudhary1310@gmail.com

O Noida, India

linkedin.com/in/hardik1310

+91-8005607433

hardikchaudhary1310.github.io/restaurant_foodii.github.io/

github.com/HardikChaudhary1310

WORK EXPERIENCE

L1 Application + Technical Support Effortech Technology

04/2024 - Present

Noida

83%

Roles/Achievements

- Coded Shell scripts to automate processes. Troubleshooting and Debugging logs to resolve day to day issues. Responsible for 24*7 availability of Infrastructure and Application
- Performing Unit-Testing Using JavaScript. Responsible for training new hires. Troubleshooting and fixing various production bugs and issues
- Implemented automation scripts using cron job scheduling across multiple applications to improve operational efficiency
- Developed and implemented automation scripts using Selenium to streamline testing processes
- Providing weekly on call rotational support for all environmental changes and client issues. Ability to quickly acquire and master new skills.
- Experienced in writing SQL queries to extract and analyze data from large databases, using various SQL tools such as MySQL, SQL Server, Oracle. Strong analytical and troubleshooting skills

System Engineer - Technology Analyst Shivalik Small Finance Bank

02/2023 - 03/2024 Noida

Achievements/Tasks

- Coding, debugging, Unit testing.Coded REST API'S Using Java.Coded UI using JavaScript, ReactJS, NodeJS, HTML, CSS
- Wrote Shell Scripts for running and scheduling Batch jobs. Wrote SQL queries to create and alter tables, retrieve data for MYSQL databases. Prepared various XML data and troubleshooted web services for various issues
- Created APIs to find Success and Failure Hits of customers
- Designing APIs using JSON format for request and response.
 Used Postman for integration testing of rest web services
- Troubleshooting and fixing various production bugs and issues.
 Involved in design discussions for various releases
- Strong technical writing and documentation skills. Able to prioritize and manage work in multi-tasking and time sensitive environments

EDUCATION

Bachelor Of Technology, Computer Science Engineering

Jaypee University of Information Technology Waknaghat, Himachal Pradesh

07/2019 - 06/2023

SKILLS

Scripting MSQL/SQL Web Development API Testing

Linux/Unix Fatal Log Analysis

Quantitate and Analytical skills Kubernetes AWS Cloud

Javascript Troubleshooting HTML/CSS/XML

GIT/GITHUB

PROJECTS

DevOps CI/CD PIPELINE (06/2024 - 07/2024)

- DevOps CI/CD PIPELINE REAL-TIME PROJECT: End-to-end lifecycle management to streamline DevOps workflows
- Maximizes development and operations teams' time by automating manual steps of the integration, delivery, and deployment processes while reducing bugs through a well-designed testing suite
- TOOLS: Git, Jenkins, Docker, Ansible

Dynamic-Web-Restaurant-Template

- Complete Responsive Website using HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, JavaScript.
- https://github.com/HardikChaudhary1310/restaurant_foodii github.io.git

Dynamic-Web-Template Static Web Template

- Using HTML, CSS and JavaScript
- https://github.com/HardikChaudhary1310/DynaminWebTemplate

ToDo Application

- Using HTML and JavaScript.
- https://hardikchaudhary1310.github.io/To do_Application/

CERTIFICATES

Google Cloud (06/2023 - 07/2023)

https://drive.google.com/file/d/1i3WMeG2NsgNqB2O_i789tljJxbxh3NJx/view?usp=drivesdk

Certification of C/C++

https://drive.google.com/file/d/0B4DBXEcxNtncdGF4QVQwalZwdkFnMmlXZnNmTUppOFUxWnVr/view?usp=drivesdk&resourcekey=0Av1rucqO9oNNHihKs_Q4bw

Frontend Certificate- HTML, CSS, JavaScript

https://www.hackerrank.com/certificates/c548574c339d

Hackerrank- Problem Solving

https://www.hackerrank.com/certificates/c548574c339d

Unix Certification (10/2024 - 11/2024)

https://drive.google.com/file/d/1Xjp2keHi9xyrBhxJ0aHZTpykrAopzSTl/view?usp=sharing